Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
C119 Villafranca, Suzanne de. New Haven, Conn. Register. 22 Oct. 1950.
C120 "A Saga of he South--." Berkeley Daily Gazette. 23 Oct. 1950.
C121 "The Women." Newsweek. 23 Oct. 1950. 101-102.
C122 Gannett, Lewis. "Books and Things." New York Herald Tribune. 25 Oct. 1950.
C123 Broomell, Sally. "Cruise of the Book Marts." Sun (West Palm Beach). 27 Oct. 1950.
C124 Bonner, Willard Hallam. " 'The Sign of Jonah' Depicts Evil Generation of the '30s." Buffalo, NY News. 28 Oct. 1950.
C125 Kane, Harnett T. "Dissecting Unpleasant Characters." St. Louis Post-Dispatch. 29 Oct. 1950.
C126 "Characters Never Dull in 'The Sign of Jonah.'" Long Beach Press Telegram. 30 Oct. 1950.
C127 "Deft Characterizations." Philadelphia PA Inquirer. 5 Nov. 1950.
C128 Govan, Christine Noble. "Little Eva et al." Chattanooga Times. 5 Nov. 1950.
C129 Hieronymus, Clara. "Tragic 'Progress' of Family." Morning Tennessean (Nashville). 5 Nov. 1950.
C130 Columbus Citizen. 12 Nov. 1950. 14.
C131 "Nancy Hale Gives Us an Irre *." Seattle Washington Post Intelligencer. 13 Nov. 1950.
C132 Field, William Noe. Best Sellers. 15 Nov. 1950.
C133 "The Sign of Jonah." King Feature Syndicate. 18 Nov. 1950.
C134 "The Sign of Jonah." Journal American. 18 Nov. 1950.
C135 Mossman, Josef. "Nancy Hale's Queer Story of Queer Eggs." Detroit News. 19 Nov. 1950.
C136 MacLaren, Hale. "Looks at Books." La Jolla, Cal. Light. 23 Nov. 1950.
C137 Laws, Nellie Gee. "Nancy Hale's New Novel Is Set in South." Nashville, Tenn. Banner. 24 Nov. 1950.
C138 Allison, Elizabeth. "Born Too Far South." Little Rock, Ark. Gazette. 26 Nov. 1950.
C139 "The New Christmas Books." San Francisco Chronicle. 26 Nov. 1950.
Harper's Magazine. December 1950: 116-120.
C140 Lysenko, Vera. "Acid Etched." The Globe and Mail. 2 Dec. 1950.
C141 "Nancy Hale's Yarn Seems Bound for Best-Sellerdom." Columbus, Ohio Dispatch. 3 Dec. 1950.
C142 O'Mara, Roger. " 'Sign of Jonah' Falls Flat." The Arizona Daily Star. 3 Dec. 1950. A.
C143 Panama, Chuck. "The Sign of Jonah." Los Angeles Evening Herald Express. 6 Dec. 1950.
C144 Pasadena, California Star-News. 3 Dec. 1950.
C145 Jackson, Margot. "Books." Beacon Journal (Akron, OH). 5 Dec. 1950.
C146 "In Brief." Cincinnati, Ohio Post. 9 Dec. 1950.
C147 O'Leary, Theodore M. "Nancy Hale Entertains with Scenes of America." Kansas City Star. 9 Dec. 1950.
C148 Barber, Kathleen L. "A Story of North-South Fusion Begins to Babble at Its Peak." The Washington Post. 17 Dec. 1950.
C149 "Acute Problems of Today Probed in One Volume." Fort Worth, Texas Morning Star-Telegram. 17 Dec. 1950.
C150 "The Gilded Years." Times-Picayune (New Orleans). Copyright Saturday Review of Literature. 17 Dec. 1950.
C151 Lord, Ruth K. "Shadows of the Deep South on New York Society." Louisville Courier-Journal. 24 Dec. 1950.
C152 Walton, Edith H. "Novelistic Hybrid." The Freeman. 25 Dec. 1950.
C153 Dodd, Marcia. "Tale of Southern Family That Shakes Society With Its Charm and Beauty." Toledo Blade. 31 Dec. 1950.
C154 "Nancy Hale, Author of 'Prodigal Women,' Writes a Scintillating Novel of Career Girls." Milwaukee Journal. 31 Dec. 1950.
C155 The Virginia Quarterly Review. Winter 1951. 150-151.
C156 McDermott, Dr. John C. "A Psychological Novel: The Sign of Jonah." Brooklyn Eagle. 7 Jan. 1951.
C157 Mavity, Nancy Barr, ed. "The Saint and the Race Question." Oakland, CA Tribune. 14 Jan. 1951.
C158 Hodges, Eva. "Roaring Twenties: A Southern Family in Gotham." Denver Post. 17 Feb. 1951.
C159 "Author Defines Her Role in Fiction vs. Reality." Minneapolis Minn. Morning Tribune. 25 Feb. 1951.
C160 Evening Standard. 11 Feb. 1952. *.
C161 Liverpool Daily Post. 5 Feb. 1952. *.
C162 "Regiment of Women." The Times Literary Supplement. 22 Feb. 1952.
Somewhere She Dances
C163 "Authoress Finds Playwriting Is Satisfying Media." The Daily Progress (Charlottesville, VA). 6 May 1953.
C164 Wranek, William H. " 'Somewhere She Dances' To Be Staged May 13." Cavalier Daily (U.Va.). 6 May 1953.
D. Awards and Recognition:
O. Henry Prizes:
D1 1933-Best Short Short Story for "To the Invader," Modern Youth. March 1933.
D2 1937 "To the North," Redbook Magazine
D3 1938 "Always Afternoon," Redbook Magazine
D4 1940 "That Woman," Harper's Magazine
D5 1941 "Those Are As Brothers," Mademoiselle
D6 1942 "Sunday-1913," Harper's Bazaar
D7 1943 "Who Lived and Died Believing" Harper's Bazaar
D8 1958 "A Slow Boat to China," Virginia Quarterly Review
D9 1966 "Sunday Lunch," New Yorker
D10 1968 "The Most Elegant Drawing Room in Europe," New Yorker
Other Awards
D11 1958 University of Illinois-Benjamin Franklin Magazine Citation for Excellence in Short Story Writing for "A Slow Boat to China"
D12 1968 Henry H. Bellamann Foundation Award for Significant Contribution to the Arts
D13 1969 Henry H. Bellaman Award for Literature for The Life in the Studio
D14 1974 Sarah Josepha Hale Award
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL 1908-88, undated, 2.5 linear feet
  This series provides an overview of Nancy Hale's life, family, and work. Materials about Nancy Hale are filed at the beginning of the series in alphabetical order. These are followed by materials about various members of her family, filed alphabetically by individual. The bulk of the family materials relate to Nancy Hale's husbands and children.
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1915-88, undated, 6.5 linear feet
  This series consists primarily of incoming with a smaller amount of outgoing correspondence. The materials are organized in two subseries Family and General, each arranged alphabetically by individual. Family correspondence consists of letters from and to Nancy Hale's immediate family plus a few cousins. The materials are arranged with those letters to or from Nancy Hale filed first followed by letters between other family members. Nancy Hale's letters from her mother and father can be found in the Hale Family Papers. General correspondence consists of primarily incoming correspondence from a wide variety of friends, associates, fans, and fellow writers. Unidentified incoming and outgoing letters are filed at the end of the subseries.
  Hale's correspondence with other writers (which is often about writing) is filed in this series. Her correspondence with agents, editors, and publishers is filed in SERIES VII. WRITINGS.
- SERIES III. DIARIES, CALENDARS, AND NOTEBOOKS 1917-88, undated, 1.5 linear feet
  This series consists of personal notes on engagements, activities, writing, dreams, psychological state, moods, health, etc., in a variety of formats ranging from line-a-day diaries to wall calendars, to individual sheets of paper. The materials are arranged chronologically.
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS 1908-88, undated, 2.25 linear feet
  This series consists of photographic prints and negatives. Prints of Nancy Hale alone are filed at the beginning of the series. They are followed photographs of family; friends and associates; places; and miscellaneous. Where negatives exist, prints have been labelled with a corresponding negative number. Negatives are filed by number in a separate box.
  [see also Oversize Materials]
- SERIES V. SPEECHES 1937-77, undated, 1.25 linear feet
  Speeches is divided into two subseries: Texts and notes and Correspondence, programs, and clippings. Text and notes consists of notes, drafts, and final versions of lectures and speeches arranged alphabetically by title or subject (if the speech has no title). Correspondence, programs, and clippings is arranged chronologically.
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES 1927-88, undated, 0.5 linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence, printed material, notes, drafts, clippings, and research material on a variety of activities, subjects, and organizations which held meaning for Nancy Hale. They are arranged alphabetically by subject, activity, or name of organization.
- SERIES VII. WRITINGS 1919-88, undated, 18.5 linear feet
  This series is divided into 10 subseries: Agents, Publishers, Early writings, Articles, Book reviews and introductions, Children's, Plays, Poems, Stories, and Books.
  Agents consists primarily of correspondence with agents negotiating for publication of works by Nancy Hale. Included are extensive office files of Elizabeth Nowell, Nancy Hale's agent from the 1930s until 1957, with a break during World War II. The Nowell files primarily document Nowell's post-war representation of Nancy Hale beginning around 1950 and ending with Nowell's death in 1957. These files include correspondence between Hale and Nowell (arranged chronologically) as well as Nowell's correspondence with publishers and agents on Hale's behalf (arranged alphabetically by the name of the firm).
  Publishers is divided into three sections Correspondence, Agreements and contracts, and Royalty reports each arranged alphabetically by firm.
  Early writings consists of manuscripts, notebooks, and correspondence with publishers about pieces written by Nancy Hale prior to 1928, the year she married, moved to New York, and began writing to make a living. They are arranged by type of material.
  Articles consists of drafts, notes, typescripts, and published versions of a variety of published and unpublished non-fiction pieces. Shorter pieces are filed in chronological order at the beginning of the series. Others are filed alphabetically by title or subject (if the piece is untitled).
  Book reviews and introductions consists of drafts, published versions, notes, and correspondence book reviews and introductions by Nancy Hale. Book reviews are filed alphabetically by the author(s) of the work. Introductions are filed by the title of the work.
  Children's consists of short stories and one book filed by title. Many of these were written in the 1980s with the aim of providing reading materials for dyslexic readers.
  Plays contains scripts, and photographs and programs from productions of the plays arranged chronologically.
  Poems consists of drafts and published versions of poems arranged chronologically.
  Stories consists of notes, drafts, and published versions of stories arranged alphabetically by title.
  Books consists of notes, research material, drafts, typescripts, reviews, publicity materials, and correspondence arranged alphabetically by title of the book. Included are 8 volumes.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - Address book undated (1980s?) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards and honors 1933-82, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baby book 1908-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography, circa 1966 circa 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical sketches circa 1959-88, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Christmas gift lists 1980-87 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings 1910s-89 (Box 1, Folder 7-13)
  - Education
    - Faulkner School 1914-18, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Winsor School
      - Correspondence 1920-25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Reports, diploma, and miscellaneous 1922-26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Class work
        - General, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - English: themes and exams
          - 1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
          - undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Report: "Elizabethan Navigation" undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Story: "Byzantine Art" undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Publication: Winsor Lamp 1924-26 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lecture notes, Philip L. Hale course at Boston University circa 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Financial 1961-87 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Houses/household
    - "Howlets," Folly Cove, Gloucester, MA 1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Woodburn," Charlottesville, VA 1957-88 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Insurance 1965-88 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Legal documents 1959-88 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Medical
    - General 1942-88, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Physical therapy 1983-87 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Speech exercises 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Memberships 1965-87 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Memorabilia
    - General
      - 1900s-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - 1961-82, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Anecdotes about Nancy Hale's childhood by her mother 1910-12 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook 1919-25 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Passports 1967-85 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Foundation application for residency, Bellagio Study Center 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Social/parties
    - Notes, lists, and recipes 1951-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Codrington Club, Oxford, England 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Fortnightly Club, Charlottesville, VA. 1986-87 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - International Sewing Society (ISS), Charlottesville, VA. 1973-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Wedding 1 1928 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Wedding 2 1935 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Family
    - General 1970-76, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Bowers, Fredson [third husband]
      - General 1959-88, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with William Wertenbaker 1956, 1985-88, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Awards and honors 1968-76, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Speeches 1954-73, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Writings 1936-83, undated (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie [father]: transcript of interview with Nancy Hale about her father undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hansell, Harriet Littell "Hal" [cousin] 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Hardin, Mark [son]
      - Telegrams and letters of congratulation on his birth 1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - General and clippings 1951-52, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - School papers and reports 1935-42, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Memorabilia 1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - St. Paul's School: correspondence 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hardin, Taylor Scott [first husband] 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Lind, Norah (Hardin) [granddaughter] 1962-70 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Littell, Anna and Elton [aunt and uncle] 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Morton, (Rosalie) Janelle (Hardin) [granddaughter] 1967-84, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Watkins, Mary Welby (Hardin) [granddaughter] and family 1970-87, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Wertenbaker, Charles [second husband] undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Wertenbaker, William [son]
      - General 1939-76, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Baby book 1938-49 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Drawings 1949, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Hill and Hollow School: correspondence 1944-46 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - School papers and reports 1942-50 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Woodberry Forest School
        - English themes 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Reports 1950-55 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Harvard University
        - Correspondence 1954-55 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - Reports and memorabilia 1955-59 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Wedding 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Writings 1961-73, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Illustrated stories by Nancy circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 14)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Family to/from Nancy Hale
    - Bowers, Fredson [third husband] circa 1942-76 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hale, H. Patterson 1977-85 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hale, John F. 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Hale, Margaret L. 1963-64 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hale, Nathan and Lillian 1963-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Hales 1951-86, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - to Hale, Lilian Westcott [mother] 1927-39 (Box 6, Folder 7-15)
    - to Hale, Lilian Westcott 1940-62, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-13)
    - to Hale, Lilian Westcott and Philip Leslie Hale 1917-29 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - to Hale, Philip Leslie [father] 1915-28 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - to Hale, Philip Leslie 1929-31 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hansell, Harriett Littell "Hal" [cousin] 1922-86, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Hardin, Sr., B. Lauristan [father-in-law] 1928 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hardin, Jr., B. Lauristan [brother-in-law] and Dorcas 1928, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Hardin, Mark (son) and Kitty [daughter-in-law] 1934-88, undated (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - to Hardin, (Rosalie) Janelle, Norah, Mary Welby [granddaughters] undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Hardin, Rosalie [mother-in-law] 1927-48 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hardin, Taylor Scott [first husband] 1927-38, 1962-75 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - Lind, Norah (Hardin) [granddaughter] and Tom 1971-88 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Littell, Anna "A'Natty" and Elton [aunt and uncle] 1914-66, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Morton, (Rosalie) Janelle (Hardin) [granddaughter] and Joshua 1969-88, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Watkins, Mary Welby (Hardin) [granddaughter] 1968-87, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Wertenbaker, Caleb [grandson] 1981-86, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Wertenbaker, Charles [second husband] 1935-51, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Wertenbaker, Julia (Cannon) "Judy" [daughter-in-law] 1967-86, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Wertenbaker, Liam [grandson] 1985-86, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Wertenbaker, William [son] 1943-88, undated (Box 9, Folder 4-8)
    - Westcott, Harriet C. "Mamama" [grandmother] 1916-30, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous relatives 1977, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Family to/from others
    - Hardin, Taylor Scott to Mark Hardin 1934-42 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Hardin, Rosalie to Mark Hardin 1935-36, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Various to Wertenbaker, William 1939-56, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Condolence on the death of Nancy Hale 1988-89 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - General
    - A 1943-87, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Abse, David Wilfred and Elizabeth 1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Allen, Helen Howe 1942-72, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - American Association of University Women 1971-73 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Arnold, Helen 1951-73 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
    - Aswell, Mary Louise 1965-81, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - B 1944-87, undated (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
    - Baker, Myles P. 1938-41 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Barach, Alvan L. 1967-76, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Bartlett, Eliot 1981-82 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Barzini Luigi 1937-38, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Battestin, Ruthe 1964-87 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Beattie, Ann 1978-80 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Beebe John 1964-88, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Benasutti, Marion 1962-74 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Benet, William Rose 1931-33 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Bevington, Helen 1961-85 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Blackford, Linda 1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Blackford, Staige 1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Bohanon, Eunice Blake 1974-77 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Bowen, Catherine Drinker 1959-73 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew and Arlyn 1963, 1971-77, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - C 1928-88, undated (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
    - Cannon, Ann and Brev 1967-87, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Chappell, Warren and Lydia 1980-83, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Chase, Mary Ellen 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ciardi, John 1960-64 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Clifford, Gay 1972-86 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Coleman, John C. 1967-88, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Cowen, Juliet 1969, 1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Crane, Joan 1970-72 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - D 1940-87, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Davis, Linda 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - De Roussy de Sales, Raoul 1931 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - DeVoto, Avis 1957-87, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dew, Robb Forman 1979-80 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dick, Hugh G. 1966-68 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Dunn, Ernestine 1971, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - E 1931-86, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Ehrenpreis, Irvin 1971-82 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Escher, John 1974-79 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - F 1937-87, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Fitts, Dudley 1962-67 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Fletcher, Lael and Bramwell 1971 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      [see also Wertenbaker, Lael]
    - Forbes, John Douglas 1975-79 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Freeman, Anne Hobson
      - 1977-79 (Box 12, Folder 23-27)
      - 1980-88, undated (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
    - G 1941-87, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Gammell, R.H. Ives 1972-80, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Gibbs, Wolcott 1930-33, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Godden, Rumer 1979 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Grierson, Margaret Storrs 1983-88 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      [see also Sophia Smith Collection below]
    - Gunther, John 1960 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - H 1913-88, undated (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Hadow, Lindsey, Lady 1968-70 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Hamburger, Philip 1969-81 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Hardman, Virginia 1977 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Harman, Lyn 1959-69 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Haydn, Hiram 1963, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Hinkle, Beatrice 1944-49, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Hoyt, Nancy undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Hughes, Mary Gray and John 1972-88 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Hyde, A. 1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - I -J 1960-86, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Jameson, Storm 1975-76 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Janeway, Elizabeth 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jefferson-Madison Regional Library 1976, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - K 1932-88, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Keith, Jack 1966-80 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Kendall, Kate and George 1966-72 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Kennison, Cynthia G. 1975 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Knowles, John 1962-86 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Koppelman, Susan 1981, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - L 1932-86, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Lago, Mary M. 1968-75 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Lamb, Vincent S. 1940 (Box 14, Folder 12A-B)
    - Lincoln, Victoria 1960?-74 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Lopatnikoff, Sally 1957-83 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - M 1942-87, undated (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - MacShane, Frank 1978 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Marzollo, Giovanna 1977-80 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Matthews, Thomas S. 1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Maxwell, William
      [see also Series VII: Writings, Publishers-New Yorker]
      - circa 1940-64 (Box 14, Folder 20-23)
      - 1965-88 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - McCord, David 1962-64, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - McCorison, Marcus 1971-82 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - McFadden, Frances 1966-82, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - McGinley, Phyllis 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - McKissock, Harriet 1974-88, undated (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
    - Mehta, Ved 1964 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Meredith, William 1961-69, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Moats, Alice-Leone 1960-75, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Moore, Pamela Robinson 1961-68, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Mumford, Lewis 1964 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Murchie, Guy, Noel, and Katie 1973-81 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - N 1936-81, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Nemerov, Howard 1962-73, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Nims, John Frederick and Bonnie Larkin
      - 1960-76 (Box 15, Folder 18-19)
      - 1977-87 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Norfleet, Elizabeth 1967, 1982-87, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - O 1943-78, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Olson, Stanley 1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - P 1942-84, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Panter-Downes, Mollie 1972-83 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Patterson, Robert 1972, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Perkins, Charles 1928-41 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Purcell, Hughey 1960-71 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - R 1933-88, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Rama Rau, Santha and Faubion Bowers 1960-65, 1980, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Raney, William 1957, 1961, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Renault, Mary 1970 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Rex, Barbara 1966-77, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Richardson, Annie 1973-88, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Ringold, Evelyn 1975, 1986-87 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Rothschild, Pauline de 1967-68, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Rowse, A.L. 1972 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Sa-Sp 1927-87, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - St-Sz 1942-87, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Saint Mary's School, Tiffin, OH 1955 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sarton May, 1965-82, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)